JEROME GALAN

EMBEDDED SOFT & HARD DEV TEST (QA & SDET)





ABOUT ME

44 years old,

Geek and passionate about technologies since my childhood. My credo is to develop and upgrade my skills every day.

"A day without learning and have fun is a day lost".

I am confident in my ability to adapt to any new situation.

Team player
Open minded
Autonomous
Communicative

LANGUAGES

- French Native
- English B2

MY HOBBIES

- Piano, Guitar, Ocarina, Harmonica
- Fencing, Lighsaber
- Astronomy
- Discover new techs

EDUCATION

Master - Université Paris 11

Electronics &
Signal processing

Bachelor

Embedded Systems & Radio comunications

SKILLS

- Specialist in real time / critical embedded software
- Specialist in SDET & QA (CI/CD Automation Tests)
- Languages (C/C++ Asm Bash Python & RUST in progress)
- MCU (TI ST Microchip Atmel Arduino DSP)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Luos - SDET/QA

SINCE 2021

Responsible of the Luos QA process and of the end to end testing strategy.

- Automate CI/CD pipeline with Github Actions: compilation, test covering, unit tests, automatic tests on a hardware benchmark, logs saving.
- Verify the process is respected, upload the release to the registry & update the lib changelog. Assist the developpers for **test quality** & unit testing.
- Specify,develop and build a testing benchmark with several MCUs
 (Arduinos, STM32, ...). Script to auto flash the MCUs with various scenarii
 binaries, auto generate the network. Develop a QA PC docker with nginx to
 and Rest API to easily access to the hardware from anywhere.

Thales - Software & SDET/QA

2010 - 2020

- Build the CI process for a whole Navy secured communication system: test of the REST API with Selenium, Robot Framework bash & python.
 BDD process. Auto generation of test documentation and results.
- QA for satellite communication systems: functionnal, performance, endurance tests. Automatic tools development. Test with Python and groovy with Jenkins environment. Test & Integration of the hardware in the Rafale airplane with the system team.
- OFDM communication protocol. Software development C/C++ on a RTOS (ucOS II). Validation in real environment.
- Drivers devloppement C/C++ & Assembly and unit tests on a DSP C6x for a satellite system. Responsible of the communication protocol between a DSP / FPGA & GPP.
- **Team leader** of the vocoder software embedded team for a HF product, and test and development (C/C++/Pyhon) on a DSP C54.
- Software development for a communication satellite in C with a DSP C54.
 Test the system and integration with the FPGA.

Alyotech - Software & Electronics

2006 - 2010

- Analogic & Digital **electronic** board **conception**.
- Automatic open/close doors system for Paris Metro: high critical security
 Firmware on a TI MCU in C and design of the analogic system.
- FPGA conception & VHDL for multibus boards (PCI, serials, USB, CAN, Ethernet ...). Design of the boards with Orcad.
- Surgical assistance: **RT software** (C & **assembly**) for ATmega & MSP-430.

JEROME GALAN

TEST LOGICIEL (QA & SDET) DEVELOPPEUR EMBARQUE

Plus de détails ici : https://aquarust.github.io











PROFIL

44 ans.

Passionné depuis mon enfance par les technologies, mon crédo est de développer et d'améliorer mes connaissances chaque jour.

"Une journée sans avoir pris de plaisir est une journée perdue".

Je suis confiant dans ma capacité à m'adapter à toute nouvelle situation.

Travail en équipe Curieux Autonome Communicatif

LANGUES

- Français- Langue maternelle
- Anglais B2

LOISIRS

- Piano, Guitare, Flute, Harmonica
- Escrime, Sabre laser
- Astronomie
- Découvrir de nouvelles techs

DIPLOMES

Master - Université Paris 11

Electronique & Traitement du signal

License

Systèmes embarqués & Radio comunications

COMPETENCES

- Spécialiste logiciel embarqués temps réél & critiques
- Spécialiste test logiciel (CI/CD Automatisation)
- Languages (C/C++ Asm Bash Python + en apprentissage: RUST
- MCU (TI ST Microchip Atmel Arduino DSP)

EXPERIENCES

Luos - SDET/QA

DEPUIS 2021

Responsable du process QA et de la stratégie de test bout en bout.

- Automatisation CI/CD avec Github Actions: compilation, tests unitaires et automatique sur la plateforme de test QA.
- Garant du process qualité, des livraisons logicielles, du *changelog*. Assiste les développeurs pour les tests unitaires.
- Développement complet de la plateforme de test multi MCUs (STM32, Arduinos ...). Scenarii de tests pour flasher les MCUs, auto générer le réseau. Dockerisation avec Nginx. API REST pour accéder au hardware.

Thales - Soft & SDET/QA

2010 - 2020

- Mise en place du CI d'un système complet de communication naval: test de l'API REST avec Selenium, Robot Framework, bash & python. Tests
 BDD. Auto generation de la documentation et des résultats.
- QA pour un système de communication satellite : tests (fonctionnel, performance, endurance). Développement des outils d'automatisation.
 Scripts Python et groovy sous Jenkins. Tests & Intégration du hardware dans un Rafale avec l'équipe système.
- Dévelopment d'un protocole de communication OFDM en C/C++sur **RTOS** (ucOS II). Validation en environnement réel.
- Développement des drivers C/C++ & Assembleur. Tests unitaires sur DSP C6x pour un satellite. Responsable du protocole de communication entre DSP / FPGA & GPP.
- Responsable d'équipe: Logiciel vocodeur d'un produit HF, Test and développement (C/C++/Pyhon) sur DSP C54.
- Développement : Satellite de communication en C sur DSP C54. Test & intégration du système avec un FPGA.

Alyotech - Soft & Electronique

2006 - 2010

- Conception de cartes électroniques analogiques et numériques.
- Automatic open/close doors system for Paris Metro: high critical security
 Firmware on a TI MCU in C and design of the analogic system.
- Conception FPGA en VHDL d'une carte multibus (PCI, serials, USB, CAN, Ethernet ...). Design de la carte avec Orcad.
- Assistance chirugicale : **soft temps réél** (C & **assembleur**) sur cibles MCU.